<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This is an automatically generated file. -->
<Chapter Label="Chapter_Combinatorics_and_Structure">
<Heading>Combinatorics and Structure</Heading>

<Section Label="Chapter_Combinatorics_and_Structure_Section_Faces">
<Heading>Faces</Heading>

<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="M, i" Name="NumberOfIFaces" Label="for IsManiplex, IsInt"/>
 <Description>
 Returns The number of <A>i</A>-faces of <A>M</A>.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="NumberOfVertices" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the number of vertices of <A>M</A>.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="NumberOfEdges" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the number of edges of <A>M</A>.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="NumberOfFacets" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the number of facets of <A>M</A>.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="NumberOfRidges" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the number of ridges ((n-2)-faces) of <A>M</A>.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="Fvector" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the f-vector of <A>M</A>.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="Facets" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the facet-types of <A>M</A> (i.e. the maniplexes corresponding to the facets).
 Currently only works for reflexible maniplexes.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="M" Name="VertexFigures" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Description>
 Returns the types of vertex-figures of <A>M</A> (i.e. the maniplexes corresponding to the vertex-figures).
 Currently only works for reflexible maniplexes.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


</Section>


<Section Label="Chapter_Combinatorics_and_Structure_Section_Posets">
<Heading>Posets</Heading>

<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="list" Name="PosetFromFaceListOfFlags" Label="for IsList"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsPosetOfFlags</Emph>. Not that the function is INTENTIONALLY agnostic about whether it is being given full poset or not.
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a <A>list</A> of lists of faces in increasing rank, where each face is described by the incident flags, gives you a IsPosetOfFlags object back.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="poset" Name="IsFull" Label="for IsPoset"/>
 <Returns><Emph>true</Emph> or <Emph>false</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Checks or creates the value of the attribute IsFull for an IsPoset.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Attr Arg="arg" Name="IsFlaggable" Label="for IsPoset"/>
 <Description>
<P/>
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset" Name="IsFlaggablePoset" Label="for IsPosetOfFlags"/>
 <Returns><Emph>true</Emph> or <Emph>false</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a <A>poset</A> (whose elements are lists of flags) corresponding to a maniplex, this function will tell you if it is flaggable, i.e., if the flags can be recovered from the poset or not.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="list" Name="ListIsFullPoset" Label="for IsList"/>
 <Returns><Emph>true</Emph> or <Emph>false</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given <A>list</A>, a poset as a list of faces ordered by rank, each face listing the flags on the face, this function will tell you if the poset is full or not.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset" Name="RankOfPoset" Label="for IsPoset"/>
 <Returns><Emph>integer</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a <A>poset</A>, returns the rank of the poset. Note: There may be hidden assumptions here to untangle later.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset" Name="IsNotFull" Label="for IsPoset"/>
 <Returns><Emph>true</Emph> or <Emph>false</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Lets me check to see if a poset is NOT full. For use in certain filtering operations.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="g" Name="PosetOfConnectionGroup" Label="for IsPermGroup"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsPosetOfFlags</Emph> with <Emph>IsFull</Emph>=false.
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a group, returns a poset with an internal representation as a list of faces ordered by rank, where each face is represented as a list of the flags it contains. Note that this function does not include the minimal (empty) face nor the maximal face of the maniplex. Note that the <Math>i</Math>-faces correspond to the <Math>i+1</Math> item in the list because of how GAP indexes lists.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="g" Name="FullPosetOfConnectionGroup" Label="for IsPermGroup"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsPosetOfFlags</Emph> with <Emph>IsFull</Emph>=true.
</Returns>
 <Description>
Returns a full poset corresponding to the connection group <A>g</A> with an internal representation as a list of faces ordered by rank, where each face is represented as a list of the flags it contains. This function does include the minimal (empty) face nor the maximal face of the maniplex, so the list has <Math>n+2</Math> ranks if the maniplex is of rank <Math>n</Math>. Note that the <Math>i</Math>-faces correspond to the <Math>i+1</Math> item in the list because of how GAP indexes lists.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="mani" Name="PosetOfManiplex" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsPosetOfFlags</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a maniplex, returns a poset of the maniplex with an internal representation as a list of faces ordered by rank, where each face is represented as a list of the flags it contains. Note that this function does not include the minimal (empty) face nor the maximal face of the maniplex. Note that the <Math>i</Math>-faces correspond to the <Math>i+1</Math> item in the list because of how GAP indexes lists.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="mani" Name="FullPosetOfManiplex" Label="for IsManiplex"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsPosetOfFlags</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a maniplex, returns a poset with the internal representation be a list of lists of faces ordered by rank, where each face is represented as a list of the flags it contains. Note that this function does include the minimal (empty) face and the maximal face of the maniplex. Note that the <Math>i</Math>-faces correspond to the <Math>i+1</Math> item in the list because of how GAP indexes lists.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="object1, object2" Name="AreIncidentFaces" Label="for IsObject,IsObject"/>
 <Returns><Emph>true</Emph> or <Emph>false</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given two faces, will tell you if they are incident. Currently only supports faces as list of their incident flags.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset" Name="FlagsAsListOfFacesFromPoset" Label="for IsPoset"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsList</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a <A>poset</A>, this will give you a version of the list of flags in terms of the faces described in the <A>poset</A>. Note that the flag list does not include the empty face or the maximal face.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset, flag, i" Name="AdjacentFlag" Label="for IsPosetOfFlags,IsList,IsInt"/>
 <Returns><Emph>flag(s)</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a flag (represented as chains of faces comprised of lists of flags) and a poset and a rank, this function will give you the <A>i</A>-adjacent flag. Note that adjacencies are listed from ranks 0 to one less than the dimension.
 You can replace <A>flag</A> with the integer corresponding to that flag.
 AdjacentFlag(<Emph>poset</Emph>,<Emph>i</Emph>,<Emph>j</Emph>) returns the <Math>j</Math>-adjacent flag to the <Math>i</Math>th flag in <Emph>poset</Emph>.
 AdjacentFlag(<Emph>poset</Emph>,<Emph>i</Emph>,<Emph>j</Emph>,<Emph>true</Emph>) will give the position of the flag.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset, i" Name="ConnectionGeneratorOfPoset" Label="for IsPoset,IsInt"/>
 <Returns>A permutation on the flags.
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a <A>poset</A> and an integer <Math>i</Math>, this function will give you the associated permutation for the rank <Math>i</Math>-connection.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection>
  <Oper Arg="poset" Name="ConnectionGroupOfPoset" Label="for IsPoset"/>
 <Returns><Emph>IsPermGroup</Emph>
</Returns>
 <Description>
Given a <A>poset</A> corresponding to a maniplex, this function will give you the connection group.
 </Description>
</ManSection>


</Section>


</Chapter>

